<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sri Kanchi Kamakoti Information and Services Center</title><link>https://kamakoti.info/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sri Kanchi Kamakoti Information and Services Center</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2020–2021, Ravikanth Chaganti and Sri Kanchi Kamakoti Peetam; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kamakoti.info/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jataka Parivarthana</title><link>https://kamakoti.info/post/jatakaparivartana/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamakoti.info/post/jatakaparivartana/</guid><description>As a part of the Jataka Parivarthana or Horoscope Exchange service, SSKISC offers to be a center for maintaining a database of horoscopes (for all communities) and exchanging these horoscopes interested parents looking for a match for their son or daughter.
The schedule for horoscope exchange at the center is as follows.
Day of Week Community Sunday Brahmin Monday Lingayat Tuesday Holiday Wednesday Vysya / Reddy / Raju / Kamma Thursday Karuba / Okkaliga Friday Yadava Saturday Others SSKISC only facilitates horoscope exchange and does not</description></item><item><title>Deerghaveni</title><link>https://kamakoti.info/post/deerghaveni/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamakoti.info/post/deerghaveni/</guid><description>Deerghaveni in sanskrit means long hair. Long hair has always been a tradition that sanatana dharma insisted for women.</description></item><item><title>Sikha Parisad</title><link>https://kamakoti.info/post/sikha-parisad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamakoti.info/post/sikha-parisad/</guid><description>Śikha means flame, powerful, ray of light, peak of a mountain. The śikha is tied back or knotted to perform religious rites. An untied śikha is a symbol of disgrace, impurity and mourning. This is not just specific only to the Brahmins but all Hindu men in ancient India had śikha. Scientifically, tying of hair applies pressure on certain parts of the head and brain and in turn results in higher levels of concentration.</description></item><item><title>Venidaanam</title><link>https://kamakoti.info/post/venidaanam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kamakoti.info/post/venidaanam/</guid><description>Venidaanam is a vedic ritual performed usually as a part of the Kasi yatra. As a part of this ritual, women offer a part of their hair to the river praying for the long life of their husbands. The husband plaits the wife’s hair, decorates it with flowers and cuts off the tip of the plait and offers it to the river. It is an interesting fact that while hair normally floats on water, at the Sangam; it immediately sinks to the river bed.</description></item></channel></rss>